Guide to the George Harrison Papers AIA.009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II. Organizations and Memberships, 1925-2000
  - Socialists Workers Party, 1984-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - South America, 1985-1988, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stop the Witch Hunts, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Taller Latinoamericano, 1983-1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Turkey Solidarity Committee, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unidad Latino Americana Malvinas Argentinas, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Unions: Labor and Workers Rights, General, 1980-1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Unions: Shell Boycott Campaign Brochures; United Mine Workers of America, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Unions: United Farm Workers of America, 1985, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - United Nations Association of the U.S., 1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - United Nations Special Committee on the Implementation of the Declaration on the Granting of Independence to Colonial Countries and Peoples, Aug 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - U.S. and Cuba Medical Project, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Anti-Imperialist League, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Friends of Ruben Zamora (Salvador), 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Hands Off Cuba Coalition, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Invasion of Panama, 1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Peace Council, 1986-1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Tour of Nicaraguan Trade Unionists, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Politicians, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1985-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Vietnam, 1982-1988 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Vietnam Tenth Anniversary Committee, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Westchester People's Action Coalition, Inc. (WESPAC), 1985-1994 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Women's Rights Organizations, 1983-1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Workers World Party, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series III. Pamphlets and Publications, 1937-2003
  Materials in this series include pamphlets and other publications produced by a variety of domestic, Irish, and international political organizations Harrison belonged to. Major topics concern Irish Republicanism, the treatment of prisoners, and international liberation movements.
  - Subseries A. Irish, 1937-2003
    - 1798 Rebellion publications, 1982-1998 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - 1916 as History: The Myth of the Blood Sacrifice. C. Desmond Greaves. (Fulcrum Press, Dublin), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Against Violence In Ireland. Desmond Wilson. (Andersontown News, Belfast), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - The Birmingham Framework: Six Innocent Men Framed for the Birmingham Bombings. Fr. Denis Faul and Fr. Raymond Murray., circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Breaking the Deadlock: A Way out of the Northern Impasse. Robert Heatley. (Fulcrum Press, Dublin), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Cabhair (Irish Republican Prisoners Defendants Fund): Dinner Journals, 1998-1999, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Casement: The Transatlantic Theatre Company Presents. Charlie Dunne., 1995 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Clan na Gael Seventieth Annual Dinner: Easter 1916-1986, Apr 25, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Corruption of Law: Memorandum to the Gardiner Committee on the working of Emergency Legislation in Northern Ireland. Frs. Brian J. Brady, Denis Faul, Raymond Murray. (Abbey Printers, Cavan), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - An Cumann Cabhrach: The Republican Aid Committee (For the Relief of Republican Prisoners and their Dependents) Testimonial Dinner, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Cumann na Saoirse/National Irish Freedom Committee: Annual Michael Flannery Memorial Dinner Dance, 2nd and 10th programs, 1996, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Michael Davitt Remembered. Bernard O'Hara. (Michael Davitt National Memorial Association. Straide, Co. Mayo), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Declaration on the Struggle again[st] Colonialism in Western Europe. Irish Republican Movement., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Unveiling of the Michael Doheny Monument. Calvary Cemetery. October 7, 1989. Michael Doheny Memorial Committee: Michael Flannery, Patrick Doheny, James Grogan. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Deported: Jimmy Gralton 1886-1945. The story of Jimmy Gralton, Effernagh, Gowel, Co. Leitrim. Des Guckian. (Westmeath Examiner Ltd., Mullingar), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Fermanagh Facts. Fermanagh Civil Rights Association., undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - The First Dail, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - The Flames of Long Kesh: The Murder of Hugh Gerard Coney, Internee, 15-16 October, 197 4. Fr. Denis Faul and Fr. Raymond Murray. (Abbey Printers, Cavan), Nov 6, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Glimpses of an Irish Felon's Prison Life. Thomas J. Clarke. (National Publications Committee, Cork), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - "Ireland's History of Repression." James Walker. Socialist Worker (reprint). International Socialists. London., undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - "Ireland's Right to Unity: The Case stated by the All-Party Anti-Partition Conference, Mansion House, Dublin." Cahill & Co. Ltd. Dublin., undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Irish-American Fenian Society: 14th Annual Awards Dinner, Oct 25, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Irish Northern Aid Testimonial Dinner Journal, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - James Connolly Wrote for Toda y.... Nora Connolly O'Brien and Eibhlin Ni Sheidhir. (Irish Freedom Press, Dublin), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Just Be. Eddie McKenna. (I.R. Publishing. Enterprise, AL), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Charlie Kerins: The 50th Anniversary Commemoration of the Execution of Charlie Kerins 1944-1994. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Labor and the Republican Movement. George Gilmore. (Repsol Pamphlet, Dublin.) (First published in 1966.), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Laochra Luimnigh: Ui Dhalaigh Luimnigh agus Eiri Amach na Casca 1916. Nora de hOir. (Clo Saoirse-Irish Freedom Press, Dublin), 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Let the Fight Go O n. Saorise Go Deao: Songs and Poems of the Irish Republican Socialist Movement. (Printing Press, Enterprise, AL) (inscribed to GH and signed by Ray Collins), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Martyrs for Ireland: The Story of Mac Cormick and Barnes. Brian O'Higgons. (Irish Book Bureau, Dublin), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Maurice O'Neill 1917-1942. [County Kerry], 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Memoirs of Irish Volunteer Activity 1917-1924. Peter O'Farrell. (West End Printing Corporation), undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Omos Do Tony D'Arcy, Galway agus Sean MacNeela, Mayo [Commemoration]. (Herald Quick Print. Tuam, Co. Galway, Ireland), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Open the Window. Let in the Light. (St. John's and Corpus Christie Parish Council Steering Committee), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Pairc an Phiarsaigh, Oscailt Oifisiul 16 Meitream. Galway [Patrick Pearce; Padraic Pearse], 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - George Plant and the Rule of Law: The Devereux Affair 1940-194 2. Michael Moroney. (Tipperary Historical Society), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Prelude to Freedom 1916-1966: 50th Anniversary Review. (Irish Art Publications, Ltd., Dublin), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Saoirse. Maria Kane. (I.R. Publishing, Enterprise, AL), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Slaying of John Downs. (Republican Publications, Dublin), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Spirit of Freedom: Prize winning entries in the Bobby Sands commemoration school essay competition. (Bobby Sands Commemoration Committee, Dublin), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Stormont: An Assessment. (United Ireland Association [Britain]) (2 copies), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - They Kept Faith: In this tribute to two soldiers of Ireland the full story of the Brookeborough attack in which they lost their lives is now told by their comrades. (Roinn Eolais Na Poblacta), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Tragedies of Kerry. Dorothy Macardle. (Irish Freedom Press, Dublin), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Ulster: The Future. Frank McManus, M.P. (Jan Press, The Bronx, NY), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - United States, Britain, Ireland: A Special Special Relationshi p. Leonard Brenner., undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Wolfe Tone Annual, 1937, 1951, 1956, 1959, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - The Workhouse Ward: A Farce. Lady Gregory, 1909. (Samuel French, London), undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Workshop Talks. James Connolly. (Repsol Ltd., Dublin), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Young Connolly. Sean Cronin. (Repsol Ltd., Dublin), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B. Non-Irish, 1980-1995
    - Africa: various, 1985-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee: Background Paper, 1983-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Center for Cuban Studies Newsletter, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Labor: Labor Against Apartheid; Phildalephia Labor Comm. on Central America; Workers Tribune; United Labor Action, 1983-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Brooklyn Chapter CIPES Bulletin: A Newsletter of the Brooklyn Chapter of Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Central America - various publications, 1982-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Chelsea / El Jicaral Sister City Project Newsletter, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The Citizen: Newsletter for the Central Brooklyn Independent Democratic Club, 1988-1989, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cuba Action, 1992-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Cuba Update, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - The 807 Teamster, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Free Puerto Rico! New Movement in Solidarity with Puerto Rican Independence and Socialism, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - The Insurgent: Newsletter of the Committee to Fight Repression, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Many Races Cultural Foundation Newsletters: The Garry Press; The Freedom Press, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Middle East: Pamphlets, 1980-1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - The New State Repression. Ken Lawrence. International Network Against New State Repression. Chicago., 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - New York Mobilizer: People's Anti-War, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - New York NICA News: Nicaragua Solidarity Network of Greater New York, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - People's Anti-War Mobilization/All People's Congress Bulletin, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Por la Paz y la Solidaridad, May 1986-Jun 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Puerto Rico: various publications, 1982-1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - The Rainbow Organizer: Official Publication of the National Rainbow Coalition Inc., 1988 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Salud y Paz: Quarterly Publication of the National Central America Health Rights Network, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Taliba: Philippine Solidarity Network Publication, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Unidad Latinoamericana Malvinas Argentinas Bulletin (U.L.M.A.), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Update on Guatemala: Committee in Solidarity with the People of Guatemala, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Various newsletters, single issues, 1984-1995 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Series IV. Oversize Materials: Publications and Fliers, 1963-1995
  Materials in this series include flyers, posters, and publications concerning American political campaigns, Irish Republicanism, and international liberation movements.
  - Commemoration Posters: John Joseph Martin, Thomas Clarke, Pronisias Stagg, Thomas Ashe Banner Memorial Committee, 1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - East Mayo Commemoration Committee, 1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fliers: South and Central America, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fliers: Various, 1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Harrison: Father of the Year Award, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Harrison Speech on British Atrocities Flier (unidentified university), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Jesse Jackson Presidential Campaign, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Political Posters and Bumper stickers: Clinton-Gore; Dinkins for Mayor [NYC], 1990-1996 (Box 17)
  - Pro-Republican Irish Solidarity Movement, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rican Committee against Repression (flier), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Ang Kasma / Ang Katipunan (Phillipines), 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Publications: April Action for Peace and Justice, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Central America, 1983-1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Fighting Back - All Peoples Congress and People's Anti-War Mobilization (2 issues), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Publications: For People and Solidarity - Bulletin of the Peace and Solidarity Project, 1986, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Publications: The Guardian vol 42, no. 17 (South Africa), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Publications: International Women's Day, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Inter-Religous Foundation for Community -IFCO News, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Publications: Leonard Peltier Defense Committee - Crazy Horse Spirit, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Publications: National Anti-Racist Organization Committee, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Publications: Palestine Focus: National Newsletter of the November 29th Coalition (various issues), 1983-1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Publications: Peace Courier Supplement, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Publications: Prisons: Fortresses of Repression, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Publications: The Socialist Campaign in '84, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Publications: United States Anti-Imperialist League, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Publications: Unions - American Workers Party, 1985; Movement for the Unity of Trade Unions and Professional Association of El Salvador, 1984; 1199US Union Slate; Workers World, 1990, 1983-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Publications: Unity (various issues), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Series V. Photographs, 1982-1998
  This series contains photographs of George Harrison's family and friends, in addition to politicians like Paul O'Dwyer and President Bill Clinton. Of note is a photograph of Bernadette Devlin McAliskey, a character witness at Harrison's trial.
  - Castro, Fidel and Angela (photoprint), undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Character Witneses: Trial (includes Bernadette Devlin), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Clinton, Bill and Hillary, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Family, 1980s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Free Joe Doherty (signed by Mary Pike; photograph includes Paul O'Dwyer) (oversize), Apr 25, 1987; Framed photograph (Box 10)
  - Harrison, George, 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Montjuic (Montjuich) Cemetery, Barcelona Spain: Mick O'Riordan, Moe Fishman, Bill Van Felix, Bob Doyle, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - St. Celsus Church, Kilkenny, Ireland, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Snee, John; Barry, Tom; Colgan, Frank, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, 1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series VI. Ephemera and Material Objects, 1950-2001
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of t-shirts, approximately 200 buttons, and other material objects acquired by Harrison beginning in the 1970s documenting anti-apartheid efforts in South Africa; anti-war and disarmament; and liberation movements in Ireland, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, Peru, Puerto Rico, Namibia, Palestine, Korea, and Cuba. The buttons also reflect Harrison's support for organized labor and union strikes, notably that against Eastern Airlines, and American political campaigns, including Jesse Jackson and David Dinkins. Posters and artwork commemorating members of the Irish republican movement from the 18th century through the 20th century, the 60th anniversary of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Harrison's membership in the Wolfe Tone and the Ninety Eight Memorial Association, and the Michael Flannery Memorial Award.
  Items added to this series in 2017 date from 1988 to 1992 and include posters related to liberation movements in South Africa, Cuba, Latin America, and Palestine, and anti-nuclear disarmament. They also include pieces of memorabilia including a ticket-stub from a 1991 Nelson Mandela rally in New York City.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade artwork and Wolfe Tone and the Ninety Eight Memorial Association Certificate, 1992-1995 (Box Shared Tamiment 054, Folder 12-13)
  - Bumper Stickers and Hats -- Palestine and El Salvador peace movements; DC 37 and Local 259, UAW-AFL-CIO, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 22)
  - Buttons: Irish, Paul O'Dwyer Campaign, Political Campaigs, USA, 1991 Teamsters Campaign R.V. Duram/Dan Kane, circa 1970-2000; 3 boxes (Box 13)
  - Buttons: South Africa Anti-Apartheid; Freedom and Human Rights: Cuba, El Salvador, Korea, Namibia, Panama, Puerto Rico, Palestine, Peru (Box 14)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Certificate (framed): Irish Wolfhounds Memorial Sculpture certficate, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Certificates: In Memoriam Paul O'Dwyer - given by George Harrison Jun 26, 1998; Inaugural Committee invitation to President Clinton's inauguration 1997, 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Commemorations (certificates and fliers): Irish Patriots (John Joseph Martin, Fr. Dominic O'Connor, Fr. Albert Bibby, Frank Stagg, Michael Gaughen, 1957 New Year's Day heroes: Sean South, Fergal O'Hanlon; Padraic Pearse, John Mitchell, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Commendation - Irish Republican Army - International Brigade, Spain. Signed by Owen Poren, Dec 1, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Copper Strike Bumper Sticker, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 065, Folder 5)
  - Cuba Information Project: Pamphlet and Cuba Libre Cocktail Recipe, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cuba Information Project: Posters, 1992 (Box Shared Tamiment AIAXOS001, Folder 3)
  - Falkland Islands Belong to Argentina: Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Irish Republican Movement Artwork, 1975-2000 (Box Shared Tamiment 069, Folder 3-4)
  - March for Peace: Event Tag, 1988 June (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Michael Flannery Freedom Medal, 1990 (Box 11)
  - Michael Flannery Memorial Award, 2001 (Box Shared Tamiment 068, Folder 2)
  - Middle East Peace March Picket Sign, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 068, Folder 1)
  - New York Welcomes Nelson and Winnie Mandela: Ticket Stub, 1990 June (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Plaques: Salue y Paz; Brinks 25 Years; personal; mirror Commemorating Easter Rising of 1916, 1978, 1991, undated (Box 12)
  - Puerto Rican Flag (small version for use in parade or festival), undated (Box 17)
  - Poster: Wolfe Tone Commemoration, undated (Box Shared Tamiment AIAXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Posters: Liberation Movements in South Africa, Cuba, Latin America, and Palestine, and Nuclear Disarmament, 1988-1992 (Box Shared Tamiment AIAXOS001, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 4)
  - Posters related to Irish-American Performing Arts, undated; 2015.043 (Box Shared Tamiment 057)
  - Save our Cities! Save our Children! March on Washington: Stationery, 1992 September (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Stop Apartheid-Boycott Shell: Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - T-shirts: Long Kesh Hunger Strike Commemoration; God Bless Union People; Committees of Correspondence (2); Mi Guevera; England out of Ireland., 2 Linear Feet (Box 15)
  - T-shirts: Nydia Velasquez for Congress; Tom Duane for Congress; Free Jim Barr; AfricanNational Congress 1992 NYC; Remember/Revisit 25 years; They May Kill the Revolutionary but not the Revolution; Irish Republican Army (Box 16)
  - Textile-painted handkerchief "Trocsardh ar La" with quote from Patrick (Padraic) Pearse, undated (Box 11)